MỸ VỊ HẦM NGỤC
I don't recognize this road.
This is the way.
Are you sure?
Pick up the pace! Get a move on!
I think we're stuck.
Don't push!
-Hey!
-Watch out--
This open space
is where we fought the Red Dragon!
You made it all the way here
on your last expedition?
Yeah.
For a long time, this spot
was believed to be the deepest point.
But recently, they found a door nearby
that seems to go even deeper.
It's engraved with a design,
and they think it opens with magic.
We came to sketch the design
for the Lord of the Island, but…
You encountered the Red Dragon
and were forced to retreat.
All right, let's try our luck.
I think we were over there last time.
I found our gear!
It's been ransacked.
No!
Yes!
I found my sleeping bag!
Great. My underwear's still here too.
Those are things you prioritize
over your valuables?
All our food is gone,
but everything else seems untouched.
Guess it was monsters that did this.
I'm so glad.
Now I can sleep warm tonight--
That's not good.
Let's find a place to rest for a bit.
I want to organize my gear too.
Maybe the snow slows down the Cleaners.
They've gotten at my soap.
Hey, none of that.
Show me whatever you just stashed away.
Here, Marcille.
Ow.
Talk about an untrained beast-man.
No wonder they slapped that collar on you.
You're called a half-foot, right?
I've never seen your kind in the East.
I had to come here
to learn about you folks.
That odd name for your race.
I heard it's because lots of you
got a foot lopped off for stealing.
Come on, you two, cut it out.
Marcille!
Come here!
It's a fish!
Is there a way to cut out
just this section?
Maybe with a magic circle…
Right. Want to give it a shot, Laios?
I'll show you how to draw a magic circle.
How's your mana sickness been lately?
I don't get so dizzy anymore.
The hallucinations
are getting stronger, though.
It's fish I used to catch
on the fourth floor.
The water from the upper floors
has flowed down here and froze.
Looks like all sorts of stuff
end up in the stream.
And now the circle's ready.
How do you feel?
A little tired.
I'll activate it then.
Imagine it as pouring water
into the symbols you've etched.
What on earth?
The ground, it's…
A-A monster?
An Ice Golem?
I see.
Hey! Above you!
Watch out!
Laios!
So how do we take this thing down?
The only way to stop Golems
is by breaking their core!
Their core?
And where do I find that?
Hey! Where's the core?
Hang on a second!
Is that its core? No, it's just a fish.
There's too much junk in there to tell.
Hey! Keep that thing distracted
and buy me some time!
I can't spot the core yet!
Huh?!
That jerk better not be making stuff up
to bring me down.
The snow!
It stopped.
Hey, you done yet?
How much longer do I have to keep this up?
That's good, Izutsumi. Well done!
Good. Perfect!
You better not be messing around!
No, idiot. Check where my arrow landed.
Also, I can use projectiles,
but I can't do much damage with them.
So don't count on me in a battle!
I'll let you handle the rest!
Oh, well.
Now that I know how to take it down…
Seems like I'm the only one here
who's actually useful.
The rest of you are just…
Is everyone okay?
It'll warm up soon.
That magic circle can get pretty hot,
so watch out for burns.
Take off your wet clothes
and dry them out.
You too.
I'll give you some cover.
Laios, can you change on your own?
Someone lend him a hand.
No need to shield me.
But you can't just…
It's not like anyone would be excited
to see a beast get naked.
What's the big idea?
I just didn't want you catching a chill.
At least let me count her nipples,
or see the base of her tail!
It's starting to get warm.
Let's prepare something hot.
We've got to thaw this out.
Maybe I can melt it over the magic circle.
Too close.
This is nice, though.
It feels like a sauna.
It's been ages since we had a bath.
Let's sweat it out!
That thing comes off?
Why am I blindfolded?
I'll clean the fish, then use the head
and bones to brew up some broth.
We might end up smelling like fish.
Thinly slice the mushrooms and Nightmares.
Give the Shapeshifter meat a quick boil
to skim off any scum.
Whisk the Harpy egg,
then mix it in with the broth
and other ingredients.
Pour it all into cups,
set them in a pot
with the Ice Golem fragments,
and heat it up.
Look. I made this out of her shed hair.
How bored are you?
Finally, garnish with Mandrake leaves.
And it's done--
Hey!
You can't just start eating on your own.
Wait until everyone is at the table.
Why not?
I took down the enemy all by myself!
I deserve to eat first!
Meals begin when everyone's present.
Chilchuck, Laios went outside.
Can you go fetch him?
Got it.
This feels great.
Is this guy for real?
ICE GOLEM SAVORY EGG CUSTARD
AND COOKED FISH
TAKEN FROM THE ICE GOLEM
All right, now that we're all here,
let's start eating!
-Let's dig in.
It's pudding.
Sorry, Marcille.
Yum!
What a waste of time.
Hey, Izutsumi.
What is it?
This is for you.
I patched up a torn bag.
You can use it.
Listen.
I apologize for calling you a beast.
I've got a sharp tongue.
Traveling together
with a bunch of strangers
can feel suffocating
and annoying at first.
But once you get used to it,
there are perks.
You can get others
to handle stuff you can't.
-That was delicious.
Yeah.
Hey, are you done yet?
Just a little longer.
Like this and that…
There we go!
Ta-da!
These are Namari's clothes,
but don't they suit her perfectly?
They're hard to move in.
It took some time to adjust them.
I got all chilled again.
I'm sorry, okay?
Well, let's hit the road.
Wait.
These are Mandrakes boiled sweet.
I figured they'd make
for good travel food.
Hey.
Have it.
That's yours.
I don't want it.
Why not?
It's really tasty.
I said I don't want it.
No, have a bite at least.
-Try it!
-I said no!
H-How mean!
Why did she have
to draw blood in this situation?
Just leave her be.
She'll eat when she's hungry.
Why don't you want it?
Because it's a monster.
Everyone says that, but how is it
different from eating animals?
If you eat monsters, you catch
strange diseases and turn into one!
That's why I won't eat it!
If eating monsters turned you into them,
it would be a simple story.
It's the idea of becoming impure.
It's not exactly logical,
but I think most people, myself included,
avoid them for that reason.
It feels like you're absorbing
something bad in some way.
And with new diseases popping up
from creatures close to humans,
I don't think vague aversion
should be brushed off so lightly.
This is really good!
But what did you do before
when you were served food you didn't like?
Before?
Ugh!
Tade, you can have this.
Thanks, Izu… I mean, Asebi!
It never happened.
I don't believe you.
Let's go, you two!
The blizzard doesn't seem to be easing up.
Maybe we should just camp here for today.
I'm hungry too.
Senshi looks worn out as well.
Let's whip something up ourselves.
What ingredients do we have left?
Nightmares, Mandrakes,
eggs, mushrooms, and…
What's this?
Any fish?
No, no more fish.
Rice then.
We're running low on rice too.
Don't you have anything better than this?
This is all we've got.
Liar! You're hiding stuff!
You can't afford to be
a picky eater in the dungeon.
You should get used to it quickly.
No!
I only eat what I want to eat!
Listen, Izutsumi.
Eating monsters doesn't turn you into one.
Has anyone turned into a sheep
or pig after eating them?
If a blind person eats an eyeball,
does that mean they'll see again?
Sheep only eat grass,
but do they turn into plants?
Food and nutrition
are more complex than that.
That's why people work hard to experiment.
Shut up!
What do you call that then?
That?
A sheep is growing into a tree.
It's a Barometz.
Why did it have to show up now?
Listen, Izutsumi.
That's a plant that always--
Shut up! I'm sick of your talk!
That's it.
I'm going to get that sheep.
What's a Barometz?
Is it some kind of monster?
It's a monster all right,
but it's harmless.
Although,
they do tend to attract carnivores.
Be careful, Izutsumi.
Who does he think he's talking to?
It's not safe to stay here.
-Let's harvest it quickly and--
-They're here.
Huh?
Dammit. Dire Wolves!
M-My staff!
Hold up!
Where are you going?
I hate dogs.
They're smelly, noisy, and persistent.
I-Is that reason enough
to just go off on your own?
I left you guys to deal with them.
You guys said friends are supposed
to make up for each other.
That's not quite what we meant.
Then what did you mean?
You didn't join in on the fight
with the Golem back there.
It's true we left that to you,
but not because of personal preferences.
Hey, let's turn back.
No.
I'm catching a whiff of fire in the wind.
If I follow it, I can find my way back.
Wait!
The scent's stronger to the right,
but the path looks rough,
so I'll go this way.
Where are you heading?
Is this the right way?
I'll take the path I want.
You should do the same.
Why don't you do as you like more?
You hate eating monsters,
and yet you still do it.
It doesn't make sense.
Well…
It seems the wolves have come after us.
Should we fight them here?
I can use explosive spells,
but I don't have my staff with me.
And it's risky to cast them
in such a confined space.
Maybe I can stun them with a bright light.
I'll run and shake them off.
What?!
Ow!
Owie.
Ow.
Hey, Asebi!
You made Tade clear off the snow
from the roof of the training hall.
I didn't.
Don't lie to me!
She fell from the roof while doing it.
Unlike you, she's clumsy,
so don't push tasks you dislike onto her!
You should show more gratitude to us
for taking you in.
Hey, Tade.
Why did you go and do something
I never asked you to do?
You really are dumb.
But Tade…
What was it she said that day?
Never mind.
I slipped up.
The explosion shifted
the wind's direction,
and I failed to notice.
Close… your eyes.
Close your eyes.
Close them!
T-Too close!
Izutsumi!
Are you alive?
Ow!
Your arm is broken.
Can you walk?
Let's rejoin the others.
Listen.
You asked me why I eat monsters,
and I've been thinking about it.
I have my goals and objectives.
I want to help my friend
and learn more about magic.
So, I'm pushing toward those goals.
Along the way,
I encounter things I dislike.
Things that are bothersome,
things that tire me,
and having to eat things I'd rather not.
Individually, none of it is a big deal.
But if I avoid everything I dislike,
I'll stray further and further
from my path.
Just like what's happening to us now.
Why did you choose
to come along with us, Izutsumi?
Because you said that
if we met the lunatic magician,
there might be a chance
to break the curse on me.
It's this way!
Exactly.
That's why you need to be ready
to take a few shortcuts.
Izutsumi! Marcille!
Are you okay?
What about you guys?
We were in a bit of a fix,
but Laios managed to scare them off,
so we're safe.
Most of the wolves
went after Marcille, anyway.
Are you hurt?
It seems she broke her arm.
I'll use recovery magic on her
while I set it back into place,
so lend me a hand.
You did great.
The recovery magic hurt more.
I was hoping to harvest a Barometz,
but the wolves made off
with the mature one.
All that was left was this unripe fruit.
Let's try cooking it.
There's a sheep inside the fruit.
I can't eat that!
It's not the same as the others,
ethically speaking. I can't eat that!
Yuck.
Slice the Barometz ribs
into appropriate sizes,
season them, and cook them.
When both sides are nicely browned,
pour in some wine,
cover with a lid, and let them steam.
Run the rind of the fruit
through hot water, remove the peel,
then chop it into chunks.
Add garlic and stew together.
Pour the finished sauce over the meat,
and it's done.
BAROMETZ BALUT (OR BAROMETZ CHOPS)
Here, cat girl.
This is yours.
It's got weird stuff in it.
That's the Barometz skin and shoots.
You should've grilled the meat on its own.
Barometz might look just like sheep,
but they taste like crab!
So what?
It's delicious.
I never knew food this amazing existed.
Come to think of it…
Tade, why did you go and do something
I never asked you to do?
You really are dumb.
Tade just wants
to be helpful to everyone.
Ow!
I mean, this place is pretty great.
We get three meals,
warm bedding, and baths too.
I can't risk being kicked out.
I'll do chores and anything else
to show them I'm useful!
Asebi,
don't lose your way just because
something is a bit bothersome.
And Lady Maizuru sometimes
rewards me with snacks.
That's what you're truly after, isn't it?
Maybe she's right.
Sometimes you do end up
with something tasty out of it.
Good for you, Izutsumi!
-Well done! Good girl!
-Good girl.
Cut it out… You…
What do you take me for, huh?!
I'll only eat when I have no other choice.
I won't be eating any vegetables
or monsters that taste bad, got it?
But you won't know if they taste bad
until you give them a try.
By the way, Marcille,
I noticed you're barely eating.
Do you really think
you can get away with not eating
after giving me that lecture?
Marcille deeply regretted
blocking her own means of escape.
Dungeon food.
Oh, dungeon food.