MỸ VỊ HẦM NGỤC
Footsteps.
What a surprise.
They really are grilling meat.
I hope they're not criminals or that sort
who aren't allowed back on the surface.
We're just camping.
We mean no harm.
Wait a minute, I know that voice.
Just as I thought!
It's you, Laios!
- Namari!
You know them?
They're my former party members.
Hey, it's been a while.
Well, I guess it's only been a week.
Oh, let me introduce these people.
These are my current employers,
Mr. and Mrs. Tansu.
They work as someone's personal scholars,
and they pay really well.
And these two are the twins,
Kaka and Kiki.
To be honest,
I can never remember who's who.
Namari, how can you act like this
after abandoning Falin?
Abandon?
I simply refused
to walk into the jaws of death for free.
You...
Marcille, take it easy.
Hey, don't push yourselves.
Falin wouldn't want
anything to happen to you.
Right.
Is there a healer in your party?
My friend needs treatment.
What do we get in return?
We have Kelpie meat.
No, thanks!
Let's go, Namari.
Handing out charity in a dungeon
just sets you up to be taken advantage of.
Seriously, even that corpse
we stumbled upon on our way here
had their own revival fee with them.
Are you going to move on ahead?
There's an Undine roaming around,
and it's dangerous.
An Undine?
So, this girl
angered a water spirit, did she?
Don't underestimate us.
We gnomes have been living alongside
gods and spirits since ancient times.
To us, spirits are like neighbors,
not something to be afraid of.
Undine!
Oh, mighty water spirit!
Heed my voice and respond to me!
This isn't working.
Grandpa Tansu!
It didn't work.
N-Namari!
Namari died!
She'll recover in no time.
Ira Fa Lane Brete Lane Bretego.
Damn you, you old geezer!
You're always using me as your shield!
That's why I compensate you handsomely!
Resurrection magic, huh?
It's a magic
I especially can't bring myself to like.
You're against resurrection?
It's not a pleasant sight to witness.
It's unnatural for the dead
to come back to life.
Outside the dungeon, sure,
but in here, it's normal.
It's not normal.
It's not normal, Laios.
That's right.
This dungeon
is under a very powerful enchantment.
It binds your soul to your body.
So, no matter how damaged your body gets,
your soul is never released.
And once your injuries are mended,
you can be revived.
In my perspective,
this isn't the dead coming back to life.
In this place, death itself is forbidden.
It is a truly dreadful curse.
But that aside,
I study such ancient spells.
I came here to investigate
a magic circle in this area,
but as you can see,
my escort isn't very dependable.
If you help me with my investigation,
I will heal your companion.
Deal.
Senshi and I will accompany you.
This should be the area.
Elven characters.
What terrible penmanship.
The roots are in the way. Remove them.
Laios, you still have that creepy sword?
I keep telling you, but--
"Use one from the shop," right? I know.
You have to get one crafted by a dwarf.
And avoid shops
that are tended by a half-foot.
And don't use the same scabbard.
And...
You should give your weapon
some care now and then!
I pity your axe!
You probably think
I'm being annoying, don't you?
No.
When it comes to handling weapons,
I trust you more than anyone else.
Stay back.
What is it?
There's a monster lurking.
Then kill it.
I don't know what or where it is.
Then how can you be certain
there's a monster?
J-Just a feeling.
Are you serious?
Mr. Tansu.
You should trust Laios
when he's like this.
I can't afford
to entertain a baseless suspicion.
If it's lurking, simply drag it out.
Oh, I see.
It's a Tentacles.
This isn't the time to admire it!
Kiki! Hang in there!
Hey, don't just stand there!
Defeat the monster already!
Our weapons can't reach it.
Hurry up and do something!
What if we purposefully let ourselves
get caught to get up close?
Tentacles is part of the cnidarian family.
If their feelers
make contact with your skin,
they shoot out venomous spines
that paralyze you.
If we get caught, there's a good chance
we won't make it out alive.
Even if you die, I'll resurrect you!
Listen...
Fine. I'll go.
Senshi, let me borrow your helmet.
Laios, you shouldn't do this!
You shouldn't count
on the success rate of resurrection magic.
It's going to be okay.
Because you and Senshi
are who I'm counting on.
- Huh? What did he mean by that?
- I don't know.
All right.
Hey! Over here, Tentacles!
Ow!
They're piercing me through my armor,
just as I feared.
My arms are already going numb.
But...
What on earth are you doing, Laios?
Target its midsection!
Its midsection!
Dammit.
So that's what he meant!
He gave me the trickiest task!
Kiki!
Laios, are you okay?
I guess not.
Wait, what?
Oh, Kiki. What happened to you?
I'll heal you right away.
This is going to be a little tricky.
Sorry, this might take a while.
Take your time.
Is it just me,
or does your face look different?
I got stung by a Tentacles.
What should I do about this?
Why are you grasping that?
When I tore it off, my hand went numb,
and now I can't let go.
Your hand looks like a gnome's now.
Let me see.
Ivy Tentacles, huh?
"Rinsing it with vinegar can reduce
some of the stingers' activity."
"It can have the opposite effect
depending on the species of Tentacles,
so proceed with caution."
"Make a cross-shaped incision
in the cross-section and peel vertically
to remove the outer layer
with the stingers."
TENTACLES WITH VINEGAR DRESSING
Apparently, it tastes pretty good.
Are you joking?
No, it's just a fun fact...
If that's the only way,
then I have no other choice.
What?
I see. It's not bad.
If prepared right,
it'll be even more delicious.
Let me have a bite, too!
This...
tastes different depending on the part!
You're definitely imagining it.
No, it's true!
Try it.
It only tastes like vinegar.
Do you want a bite, too, Marcille?
Huh? What is it?
It tastes sour.
It's kinda gooey.
- It's taro root. Tell me it's taro root.
- You, too, Namari.
This part. I recommend this part.
No! No, thanks!
We're not lacking food!
It tastes good, though.
Not quite,
but it could be if prepared right.
Either stew it or mash it and then fry it.
Sounds good!
It slipped off!
Sorry for the wait.
I'll treat you now.
Thank you.
Well then, please heal her first.
Ilava Rietge Atheus Pilitos
Nuswera Iboiseme Seus Wehrba.
It feels awesome being in good health!
Thank you, Mr. Tansu.
You, too, Laios.
What's with your face?
Thank Namari instead.
What?
Your marksmanship was truly remarkable.
It's amazing you took it down
with just one shot.
We're lucky you're skilled
with a crossbow, too.
Actually, it was my first time using one.
What?
Namari.
Thanks for giving us a hand.
I'll set aside the incident
with Falin for now.
You're most welcome.
Getting paid makes you give it your best,
more so than doing it for free.
Now, now, you two.
It's all in the past now.
It totally isn't!
Why are you, of all people,
acting like it's none of your business?
Unbelievable!
- That's not what I meant!
- Are you the leader?
Tough role, huh?
It's looking this way.
Is it still upset?
What did you do
to make the spirit so furious?
I've never been attacked by one
so fiercely before.
I may have accidentally poured
boiling water directly onto it.
That's not good. Typical of an elf.
Elves...
My race has nothing to do with it!
Is there a way to pacify the spirit
without using magic?
That's simple.
An Undine is a collective of tiny spirits.
If the individuals comprising it
naturally dies off,
their hostility will fade away
as new generations emerge.
The lifespan of a spirit
is a week at most.
A week?
I can't wait that long.
Neither can we.
So, we will return to the surface for now.
We'll resume our investigation
another time.
Hey, let's prepare the return spell.
Hey, Laios.
They're preparing the return spell.
Mr. Tansu, I have a favor to ask you.
You want me to return
to the surface with them?
Now? After coming all this way?
You're currently out of magic.
I've heard that running out of magic
is similar to having anemia.
You should head back to the surface
with Mr. Tansu's party.
I'm fine.
I'm actually quite surprised
by how great I feel.
Oh, I think it might be due to the liver.
Eating nutritious food won't result
in immediate changes to your condition.
- It's one's daily--
- I'll listen to that later.
I really feel fantastic.
I think some of my magic returned as well
after a short rest.
But your staff doesn't seem
to have the usual magical aura.
T-That's because...
Let's leave her.
Why are you laughing?
It's just that I've never seen you
with that expression before.
But...
what are you going to do
when you're on your own?
The three of you
can't fight a dragon by yourselves.
Don't count me in.
Plus, that axe of yours doesn't seem like
it could harm a dragon in the slightest.
Namari, you've defeated
many dragons, right?
Yeah.
Well then...
Please, Namari.
Rejoin our party!
Are you serious?
Help Laios' party defeat the Red Dragon.
I want to rescue Falin, no matter what!
Just this once!
I'll find a way to gather the funds!
Forget it, Marcille.
Why?
The adventurer community is small.
Gossip travels like wildfire.
Namari has been having
financial problems for some time now.
And you got wind of it,
didn't you, Mr. Tansu?
I did.
Now, imagine if she rejoined
her former party for money.
"She'll do anything for the right price."
That's what people will say about her.
It may open up more job opportunities,
but it'd probably attract
a different clientele.
So, forget it.
Especially if you care
about both your futures.
That's how it is.
Forget it, Marcille.
No. There's still another way.
There's another way for me
to regain my magic.
W-What is it?
I drink...
the Undine!
What? The Undine?
What's with your reactions?
Where's your usual enthusiasm?
I'm not so interested in spirits.
Spirits live on magic.
I'm certain they're abundant
in magical energy!
Capturing it seems trickier
than defeating it, though.
But water spirits are vulnerable to heat,
so maybe I can use that.
Maybe we can attack it
with a heated weapon.
Or maybe we can pour oil on the lake,
set it on fire, and trap the spirit?
When it attacks, it spills on the ground,
and maybe I could quickly drink that.
It'd probably poke holes
in your body from the inside.
You're right.
Come on, think.
There must be a way.
By heating this pot
and using it as a shield,
I could defend and attack simultaneously.
Undines are powerful enough
to penetrate a stone column, though.
You think that shabby pot can protect you?
It's unfair to call it a shabby pot.
It's a family heirloom that's been
passed down through generations.
I have diligently maintained it.
It never gets burnt
and it distributes heat evenly.
It's an exceptional pot.
Hold on.
The color, the sheen,
the weight, the texture...
This is adamant!
Unbelievable.
As a weapon,
it can shatter a dragon's bone.
As armor,
it shields even against a dragon's fangs.
Adamant, the metal
that every blacksmith dreams of.
So, why is it used for a pot?
It was originally a shield,
but I had no need for it, so...
How can you be so wasteful?!
Do you think it could withstand
an Undine's assault?
Of course, it could!
We happen to have both a pot and a lid,
so two of us can wield one each
to attack it from both sides...
And we'll burn it with fire!
It's the only option we have.
Really?
Even if they have tough shields,
the Undine is so powerful.
Maybe the dwarf could restrain it,
but is Laios strong enough?
Brace yourself as soon
as the surface starts to warp.
Let's not waste this opportunity.
Here comes!
Laios!
What incredible power!
Namari...
Now!
Good. Keep going.
Hang in there!
Place it over the flames!
So hot!
- Wow, this is amazing!
- Incredible.
What astounding strength!
Namari, Senshi, thank you so much!
You, too, Laios.
Are you okay?
Despite his physique, he's pretty flimsy.
Just like a typical tall-man.
Right.
No need to drink it all in one go.
Spirit magic is hard to absorb.
It's fundamental to pair nutrition
with something that aids in absorption.
Senshi.
Let's start cooking.
Peel the potatoes, carrots,
onions, and the Tentacles.
Then cut them into bite-sized pieces.
Marinate the Kelpie meat
with salt and pepper,
and fry until the surface changes color.
Add the onions and carrots
and sauté them together,
then put them into the Undine.
Skim well,
then add the potatoes
and spices and simmer.
It's done!
UNDINE STEW WITH TENTACLES AND KELPIE
Huh? Where did everyone go?
They went to continue their investigation
at the tower across the water.
We're back!
I had no idea there would be so many.
Good thing we dealt with them.
H-Hey!
Would you like to join us for a meal?
Here you go.
Looks good.
Did you make this, Marcille?
Senshi helped a lot.
Here, Namari.
You should start eating
instead of serving everyone.
O-Okay.
Yes!
Some magic is starting to come back.
You guys,
did you come this far
while scavenging all this time?
Yup.
I was ready to face criticism
for leaving the party,
but I never expected
to see them resort to this.
Maybe this is a form of punishment.
It's delicious! The broth
has been infused into the ingredients.
How did everything cook so quickly?
Is it because of the pot?
Could adamant
be a good material for making pots?
Senshi, was it?
Um, about your axe...
I apologize for making fun of it.
It's all right.
The truth is, I have no interest
in any blacksmithing work.
I can't distinguish
different types of ore,
and my old friends
used to get frustrated with me often.
Namari, we're heading back to the surface.
But you can stay here.
What are you talking about?
Try a bite at least!
The texture is a bit odd,
but it tastes quite good!
But...
I know I can't ask you to trust me...
but I want to be more
than just a hired hand.
I want to be accepted as one of you.
I'll work hard.
Frankly, Chilchuck,
I thought you'd be the first one
to leave the party.
You're not the kind to accept unpaid work.
Damn right.
That's why I always insist
on getting paid upfront.
But the problem is that I can't walk away
when situations like this arise.
What? You stayed because it was your job?
Not for your friends or friendship?
Listen, Marcille.
Let me tell you something important.
Folks who claim
they don't need anything in return
are the least trustworthy in this world.
By the way, what's Shuro up to now?
No idea.
He seemed to have
another contact to reach out to.
But he was so in love with Falin
that he wanted to propose to her.
So, he's probably still
desperately searching for her.
What? I had no clue.
- He's so oblivious.
- Totally.
Look, I get that you guys
all care about Falin, but be sure
to make it back to the surface, okay?
Namari, you take care, too.
See ya!